Guide to the Paul A. Samuelson papers, 1933-2010 and undated RL.10082
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Speeches and Interviews Series, 1980-2009, 8 boxes
  - Speeches and interviews, 2001
    - 373. "Analyzing the Great Debate About Globalization," Belmont Hill School, Belmont, Mass., 19 October 2001 (Box 125)
    - 374. "Something of Myself as a Productive Scholar," Harvard Business School Seminar with Robert Merion (Tom McCraw), 19 November 2001 (Includes VHS tape) (Box 125)
    - 375. "Salutation at Bank of Sweden," Nobel Centennial Dinner, Swedish National Gallery, Stockholm, Sweden, 7 December 2001 (Box 125)
  - Speeches and interviews, 2002
    - 376. "Current U.S. and Global Uncertainties," Sarasota Institute of Lifetime Learning, Sarasota, Florida, 8 January 2002 (Box 125)
    - 377. "Some Personal Rememberings of Joseph Schumpeter," Schumpeter Society meeting, Gainesville, Florida, 28 March 2002 (Publication No. 2183) (Box 125)
    - 378. "A Few Theoretical Aspects of Deregulation," NYU Lecture, 4 April 2002 (Publication No. 2145) (Box 125)
    - 379. "Pure Theory Aspects of Industrial Organization and Globalization," NYU Technical Symposium, 5 April 2002 (Publication No. 2146) (Box 125)
    - 380. Radio interview for Radio Svizzer by phone, February, 2002 (Includes audio cassette tape) (Box 125)
    - 381. "Remembering Jim Tobin," Memorial Service, Yale, New Haven, Conn., 27 April 2002 (Box 125)
    - 382. "A New Thing Under the Sun," Commencement Address at Boston University, School of Management, Boston, Mass., 8 June 2002 (Box 125)
    - 383. Interview (in Portuguese) for CartaCapital (Brazil), 29 May 2002 (Box 125)
    - 384. "Crisis in American Capitalism," On Point radio talk show, WBUR, 23 July 2002 (Includes audio cassette tape) (Box 125)
    - 385. "Tale of Two Macroeconomics," NYU Lecture, 19 November 2002 (Publication No. 2162) (Box 125)
    - 386. "Where Economics and the Global Economy Seem To Be Going," Lawrence Kotlikoff's group at Boston University, Boston, 22 November 2002 (Includes audio cassette tape) (Box 125)
  - Speeches and interviews, 2003
    - 387. "Salutations to TIAA-CREF Victors," read at TIAA-CREF Paul A. Samuelson Award, AEA, Washington, DC, 5-6 Janumy 2003 (Box 125)
    - 388. Interview (in Italian) in L'espresso, 16 January and 23 January 2003 (Box 125)
    - 389. Interview (in Japanese) in Bloomberg News Collection, January 2003 (Box 125)
    - 390. "Economists Take on Bush," On Point talk show, WBUR, with Milton Friedman, 12 February 2003 (Includes DVD) (Box 125)
    - 391. No copy (Box 125)
    - 392. "The Economy, Now and in Years Ahead," National Heritage Museum, Lexington, Mass., 7 September 2003 (Includes audio cassette tape) (Box 125)
    - 393. "Remembering Charlie" (Kindleberger), Memorial tribute, MIT Chapel, 30 October 2003 (Box 125)
    - 394. Professors Samuelson and Solow on Franco Modigliani, for ISEO, Italy, 13 November 2003 (Includes VHS tape) (Box 125)
    - 395. "Abram Bergson, Economist," Memorial tribute, Memorial Chapel, Harvard University, Cambridge, Mass., 24 November 2003 (Box 125)
    - 396. "Franco, Dear Friend and Wonderful MIT Colleague," Kresge Auditorium, MIT, 7 December 2003 (Publication No. 2334; Includes DVD of service) (Box 125)
  - Speeches and interviews, 2004
    - 397. "The Not-So-Dismal Science of Economics: An Attempt to Be Realistic About Present and Future Trends," Phi Beta Kappa Club, Sarasota, Florida, 24 January 2004 (Box 125)
    - 398. "Walt Whitman Rostow 1916-2003," memorial symposium, Lyndon Baines Johnson Library, Austin, Texas, 6 February 2004 (Box 125)
    - 399. Interview on outsourcing/globalization, On Point talk show, WBUR, 27 September 2004 (Includes audio cassette tape) (Box 125)
    - 400. "A Life in the Cheerful Discipline of Economics," Analysis Group Senior Staff meeting (Martha Samuelson), Cambridge, Mass., 20 October 2004 (Box 125)
    - 401. No copy (Box 125)
  - Speeches and interviews, 2005
    - 402. "Appreciation of Robert Solow as Creatively Original Scholar," ECAAR dinner at AEA, Philadelphia, Penn., 8 January 2005 (Box 125)
    - 403. No copy (Box 125)
    - 404. "Tribute to the NYU Experience," NYU Lecture, 8 April 2005 (Box 125)
    - 405. "Learning From Allies and Unadmired Contemporaries: Picking Modigliani's Pros," and "Final Valedictory Words," The New School, New York, 14 April 2005 (Box 125)
    - 406. "Serendipity," 90th Bilthday Party (MIT), Fairmont Copley Plaza, Boston, Mass., 15 May 2005 (Box 125)
    - 407. "Modern Finance Theory in One Lifetime: Being 'In on the Creation,'" Boston College, 3 June 2005 (Box 125)
    - 408. Interview for Der Spiegel, 20 July 2005 (Box 125)
    - 409. Interview (in Japanese) in Nikkei/Nihon Keizai Shimbun, 3 August 2005 (Box 125)
    - 410. "Beantown, the Athens of Finance," Boston Security Analysts Society, Boston, Mass., 15 November 2005 (Includes audio cassette tape) (Box 125)
    - 411. Telephone interview for German (Sunday) newspaper FAS, 6 December 2005 (Box 125)
    - 412. Interview for Der Spiegel, 5 December 2005 (Box 125)
    - 413. Q&A for The People's Daily (China), 14 December 2005 (Box 125)
    - 414. Article on greatest economists of all times (in French) in L'Expansion, pg. 86, December 2005 (Box 125)
  - Speeches and interviews, 2006
    - 415. Comments read at TIAA-CREF Paul A. Samuelson Award, AEA, Boston, Mass., 6 January 2006 (Box 125)
    - 416. Interview with Robert Merton for the American Finance Association website, Spring 2006 (Includes DVD) (Box 125)
    - 417. "Great Minds in Economics," interview in Yale Economic Review, Vol. 2, Issue 3, pgs. 39-42, Summer 2006 (Box 126)
    - 418. "Tribute to Zvi Bodie and His New Chair," Boston University, Boston, Mass., 5 June 2006 (Box 126)
    - 419. Tribute to Eytan Sheshinski on his 60th birthday, 6 June 2006 (Box 126)
    - 420. Notes on "Global Competition and Comparative Advantage," conference at Woodrow Wilson International Center for Scholars, with Ralph Gomory and Will Baumol, Washington, DC, 13 June 2006 (Box 126)
    - 421. "Key Likely Global Trends: Past and Future," Barcelona Corporate Executives, Harvard Faculty Club, Cambridge, Mass., 8 July 2006 (Box 126)
    - 422. "A Few Academy Memories," American Academy of Arts and Sciences induction ceremony, 7 November 2006 (Box 126)
    - 423. No copy (Box 126)
    - 424. Interview for "Nobel Thinkers," December 2006 (Includes DVD) (Box 126)
  - Speeches and interviews, 2007
    - 425. Interview for Bloomberg Radio, 16 January 2007 (Includes CD) (Box 126)
    - 426. "Surgeon General Warns Financial Engineering May be Dangerous to Society's Health?" Keynote speech, JOIM Conference, Boston, Mass., 23 September 2007 (Box 126)
    - 427. "Economist Dogs That Did Not Bark," MIT panel discussion, MIT, 1 October 2007 (Box 126)
    - 428. "Joseph Keenan: Engineer, Scholar and Neighbor," MIT Symposium on Keenan, Museum of Science, Boston, Mass., 4 October 2007 (Box 126)
    - 429. "E. Cary Brown (1916-2007)," MIT Memorial Service, MIT Chapel, 12 October 2007 (Box 126)
    - 430. "Agnete Kalckar (1913-2007)," Memorial Service, Cambridge, Mass., 20 October 2007 (Box 126)
    - 431. Interview on the economy for Bloomberg (Tom Keene), 15 October 2007 (Includes DVD) (Box 126)
  - Speeches and interviews, 2008
    - 432. Abridged version of #431, Bloomberg Magazine, Vol. 17, No.1, pg. 154, January 2008 (Box 126)
    - 433. "The Father of Financial Engineering," interview in Bloomberg Markets, pgs. B-F, April 2008 (Box 126)
    - 434. "Tribute to Peter Temin," Retirement Celebration, The American Academy of Arts and Sciences, 10 May 2008 (Box 126)
    - 435. Interview (in Japanese) for Nikkei Business Management, April 2008 (Box 126)
    - 436. Interview (in German) in Die Zeit, pg. 29, 10 July 2008 (Box 126)
    - 437. "What Retirement Means To Me," panel discussion with Robert Solow and Robert Merton, Life-Cycle Saving and Investing Conference (Zvi Bodie), Boston University, Boston, 23 October 2008 (Box 126)
    - 438. Interview in Asahi Shimbun, 31 October 2008 (Box 126)
    - 439. Interview (in Japanese) in Yomiuri Shimbun, 13 November 2008 (Box 126)
    - 440. Interview (in German) in Der Spiegel, pg. 69, 10 November 2008 (Box 126)
    - 441. "A Few Quasi-Heresies," Harvard Undergraduate Economic Associate, Cambridge, Mass., 9 December 2008 (Box 126)
    - 442. "Informal Remarks about the 2007-2010+ Global Financial Meltdown," Plymouth Harbor, Sarasota, Florida, 18 December 2008 (Box 126)
    - 443. "Helping the Poor to Become Less Poor," Launch of the MIT Legatum Center, MIT, 7 October 2008 (Box 126)
  - Speeches and interviews, 2009
    - 444. Interview (in Spanish) in La Vanguardia, 18 January 2009 (Box 126)
    - 445. "Don't Expect Recovery Before 2012-with 8 Percent Inflation," interview (on-line), Global Economic Viewpoint, New Perspectives Quarterly, Vol. 26, No.2, Spring 2009 (Box 126)
    - 446. Interview in Roads to Wisdom, Conversations with Ten Nobel Laureates in Economics, Karen Ilse Horn. Cheltenham, UK and Northampton, MA: Edward Elgar, pgs. 39-57, 2009 (Box 126)
    - Interview clip in BBC Business Daily, December 2009; 3.6 Megabytes; 1 MP3 audio file; approximately 3 megabytes.
- Teaching Materials Series, 1943-1983, 4 boxes
  Class notes, required reading lists, "Courses by Newspaper" booklets, syllabi, and other materials from courses taught by Samuelson at Harvard, MIT, and other universities.
  - Courses and teaching materials, 1943-1978 (25 folders) (Box 127)
  - Courses and teaching materials, 1952-1974 (29 folders) (Box 128)
  - Courses and teaching materials, 1967-1983 (22 folders) (Box 129)
  - Courses and teaching materials, 1952-1979 (23 folders) (Box 130)
- Unpublished Writings Series, 1933-2009 and undated, 26 boxes
  Samuelson's unpublished and unfinished writings make up the majority of the series. To allow for better access, these unorganized files were sorted into fifteen topical groups: Economic Policy, Financial Economics, Growth Theory, History of Economic Thought, International Economics, Macroeconomics, Marx, Mathematical Economics, Population and Gender, Public Economics, David Ricardo, Piero Sraffa, Stochastic Theory, Thermodynamics, and Welfare Economics. Finally, there is a remaining group of uncategorized folders of unpublished writings, and then two boxes of notes and fragmentary writings.
  Jotted down on notepads and paper sheets and frequently informal in tone, the unpublished writings reflect Samuelson's interest, manifest throughout his career, in multiple areas of scientific and historical thought. The most prolific output relates to mathematics and mathematical economics. The history of economic thought also receives a great deal of attention from Samuelson, with extensive writings on classical and neoclassical economics and separate categories for his many notes and drafts on the economic thought of Karl Marx, David Ricardo, and Piero Sraffa. Samuelson contributed seminal work to the new field of biological economics, helping to shed light on sex ratios and population issues in economics, and this work is present in this series in the form of writings on population and gender and on Volterra and Lotka. The series ends with uncategorized unpublished writings on a variety of issues ranging from capitalism and utility analysis, to comments on published articles by other economists.
  The fifteen categories are arranged alphabetically, then alphabetically within by original folder titles.
  - Economic Policy
    - 1988 economic predictions, 1987 (Box 131)
    - The alleged Americanization of Europe, undated (Box 131)
    - Armament expenditure and gross corporate saving, 1940-1942 (Box 131)
    - Bogeyman for Japan: A Kondratieff downsizing?, 1982 (Box 131)
    - The case for McGovern, 1972 (Box 131)
    - Common market, undated (Box 131)
    - Disparity in post-war exchange rates, 1940s (Box 131)
    - Economic conditions, lecture notes (public speech), 1980s (Box 131)
    - Economic Policy, 1990s (Box 131)
    - Economic priorities for the 1970s, 1973 (Box 131)
    - Fallacies and truths about present world "meltdown," undated (Box 131)
    - Notes on current and future monetary policies, undated (Box 131)
    - Notes on Larry Summers' comments on pollution, 1992 Feb. (Box 131)
    - Notes prepared for McNeil-Lehrer interview (cancelled), 1989 Jan. (Box 131)
    - On social security, 1976 (Box 131)
    - Policy agenda for late 1980s, 1986 (Box 131)
  - Financial Economics
    - Avoiding bias in judging commodity funds, 1987 (Box 131)
    - The backward art of investing money, 2004 (Box 131)
    - A case study of arbitrage and risk, undated (Box 131)
    - Current state of the theory of interest rates, with special reference to mortgage rates, undated (Box 131)
    - Derby (horse racing and betting), undated (Box 131)
    - Economic portfolio theorem, 1982 (Box 131)
    - Enjoying gambling as such, 1995 (Box 131)
    - Equilibrium structure of security yields under uncertainty, 1960s (Box 131)
    - Friedman-Savage geometry and revealed preferences, 1991 (Box 131)
    - A fundamental advantage of debtors, 1971 (Box 131)
    - A Fundamental theorem that ideal speculative price is unbiased, undated (Box 131)
    - The gains from trade one more time, 1978 Aug. (Box 131)
    - Gambler's ruin and sequential analysis: I. Fair games, undated (Box 131)
    - General equilibrium model for parimutuel racetrack odds, 1990 (Box 131)
    - How now Dow and the economy?, 1987 (Box 131)
    - Keynes on risk, 1976 (Box 132)
    - Mathematical notes on stocks and investments: I. Formula Plans, 1976 (Box 132)
    - A more general theory of arbitrage suggested by a second experiment, 1950s (Box 132)
    - Nonlinear productivity through the spectrum is white, 1980 (Box 132)
    - Notes on the distribution of income resulting from differential attitudes of rich and poor toward profitable risks, 1964 (Box 132)
    - Opiates and mantras of the left and right, 1988 Aug. (Box 132)
    - Optimal forward hedging, 1970 (?) (Box 132)
    - A paradox of risk, 1960s (Box 132)
    - Proof that high tax rates warrant a relatively high price-earnings ratio, 1974 (Box 132)
    - Return needed to justify investing in futures, 1987 (Box 132)
    - Theoretical analysis of equity prices, 1979 (Box 132)
    - A theory of arbitrage and risk, undated (Box 132)
    - Two reflections on the Random-Walk Model of price changes, 1968 (Box 132)
    - Wicksellian interest scenarios with or without "Missing Equation(s)," 2001 (Box 132)
  - Growth Theory
    - The autonomous second-order system, 1976 (Box 132)
    - The canonical model of capital, undated (Box 132)
    - Chapter 59: The Era of Accelerated Growth, 1957-1973, 1976 (Box 132)
    - The classical canonical growth model in modern garb: comparative statics and dynamics, 1991 (Box 132)
    - Comments on a multi-sector plowed-back savings model, 1969 (Box 132)
    - Distinctness of the Hicks and Harrod definitions of neutral technology change, circa 1965 (Box 132)
    - Economic development looked at from the standpoint of a theorist, 1978 (Box 132)
    - Efficient paths of dynamic capital development, undated, 2 folders (Box 132)
    - Evaluation of "Social Income": Capital formation and wealth, 1960 (Box 132)
    - Evaluation of social income: II. Capital formation and uncertainty, undated (Box 132)
    - Foreword on The Theory of Capital and Growth, undated (Box 132)
    - The fundamental identity between the minimum-factor-price and per-capital-consumption frontier: The Neoclassical Case, 1969 (Box 132)
    - Kaldor's alternative distribution models, 1987 (Box 132)
    - Kaldor's alternative distribution models, 1988 (Box 133)
    - Kondratieff waves as science fiction, 1983 (Box 133)
    - Luigi Pasinetti Paradox, 1985 (Box 133)
    - Moynihan and Modigliani, undated (Box 133)
    - Reflections on the political economy of development, 1971 (Box 133)
  - History of Economic Thought
    - Adam Smith, 1990s (Box 133)
    - Advance of total factor productivity from entrepreneurial innovations, 2006 (Box 133)
    - Böhm-Bawerk: Continuous input-point output, undated (Box 133)
    - The Bortkiewcz Solution, undated (Box 133)
    - Classical economics, 1990s (Box 133)
    - Classical economics (Smith to Ricardo) centered around the concept of surplus product, undated (Box 133)
    - The classical universal tradeoff between wage rate and profit rates is false, 1994 (Box 133)
    - Comments on Lekachman biography of John Maynard Keynes, undated (Box 133)
    - Contrafactual economic history based on variations of 1799 Malthus and 1912 Schumpeter, 2006 (Box 133)
    - Creativity in science, 1960s (Box 133)
    - Deeper versions of Thünen's magisterial 1850 "Neoclassical" marginal productivity of distribution, 2005 (Box 133)
    - Economic history and mainstream economics analysis, 2001 (Box 133)
    - Economists in two wars (Schumpeter), undated (Box 133)
    - First draft of pamphlet on 1918-1920 period, 1943 (Box 133)
    - First-order homogeneity of the production function, undated (Box 133)
    - The jewel hidden in the classical system: augmented (dated) land contents provide "natural" price constants, 1996 (Box 133)
    - The Labor-and-Energy Theory of Price, 1975 (Box 133)
    - The labor theory of value, undated (Box 133)
    - The life of John Maynard Keynes, undated (Box 133)
    - Marginal costs to the rescue of the labor theory of value, 1984 (Box 133)
    - A model of classical monetary theory, undated (Box 133)
    - A modern history of history of economics, 1990 July (Box 133)
    - Money at the University of Chicago, undated (Box 133)
    - Neoclassical economics, 1985 (Box 133)
    - Neoclassical Thünen, 2006 (Box 133)
    - Notes on Irving Fisher, 1990s (Box 133)
    - Notes on Schumpeter, 2004 (Box 133)
    - Politics, ethics, and economics, 1951 (Box 133)
    - Probability and cardinal utility: a digression, undated (Box 133)
    - Refutation of logically-necessary Paretian income inequality, 1975 (Box 133)
    - Remembering Schumpeter, 1992 (Box 133)
    - The revealed preference approach: a digression (Box 133)
    - Rules of the game, 1975 (Box 133)
    - The Schumpeter I Knew, undated (Box 133)
    - Schumpeter as a teacher and economic theorist, undated (Box 133)
    - Stolper on Schumpeter, at last, 1995 (Box 133)
    - Thünen: an economist ahead of his time, 2008 (Box 134)
    - Thünen's magnificent neoclassical distributive theory ahead of its time, 2005 (Box 134)
    - Thünen's rings of specialization by factor-price equalization process, 1974 (Box 134)
    - Thünen's space model deduced by general equilibrium analysis, 1974 (Box 134)
    - Transforming from Labour-Theory-of-Value to socially efficient pricings, 1986 (Box 134)
    - Untitled (classical and neo-classical economists), undated (Box 134)
    - Variations on a theme by Hicks and Ricardo, 1971 (Box 134)
    - War and the pound, undated (Box 134)
  - International Economics
    - America's interest in international trade, 1979 (Box 134)
    - Analyzing Warren Buffett's scheme that enforce equality of U.S. imports and exports, 2008 (Box 134)
    - Arthur F. Burns on the efficiency of comparative advantage, 1987 (Box 134)
    - Autopsy of enforcing zero trade balance, undated (Box 134)
    - The effect of a unilateral payment upon the terms of international trade, 1937 (Box 134)
    - The effects of a tariff upon a commodity's price, undated (Box 134)
    - Equilibrium in international trade in terms of the Keynesian theory of income determination, 1960s (Box 134)
    - Erik Lundberg (1907-1987): an international appreciation, 1989 (Box 134)
    - Exchange equilibrium and parity, 1947 (Box 134)
    - Factor proportions and international trade theory, undated (Box 134)
    - Foreign trade multipliers with several countries, undated (Box 134)
    - The gains from trade one more time, 1978 Aug. (Box 134)
    - Homeostasis of factor prices under free trade: analogies and typographies, 1981 (Box 134)
    - How to see that trade reversals are actually Pareto Efficient, 1979 (Box 134)
    - How transport costs teleologically make geographical production and trade patterns determinate, 1982 (Box 134)
    - International corporations and the future of foreign trade, 1973 (Box 134)
    - New order coming, 1977 (Box 134)
    - Notes on development of Factor-Price Equalization doctrines, 1980 (Box 135)
    - On international trade theory (Bhagwati), undated (Box 135)
    - A one-treadable-good model to dramatize equilibrium capital movements that are not zero, 1995-2004 (Box 135)
    - Problems in the definition of equilibrium exchange rates, undated (Box 135)
    - The relationship between changes in exchange rates and general prices, 1934 (Box 135)
    - Revisiting the Ohlin-Keynes debate on burdens from reparation or other unilateral payments, 2005 (Box 135)
    - Summing up on factor price equilibrium in models with capital goods and time phasing, 1982 (Box 135)
    - A synthesis for "monetary" and other approaches to international economics, 1980 (Box 135)
    - U.S. versus Europe production patterns, undated (Box 135)
    - When the good fairy will want to prescribe a balance of payments deficit for the American people, 1994 (Box 135)
  - Macroeconomics
    - Alvin Hansen and the interactions between the Multiplier analysis and the principle of acceleration, 1959 (Box 135)
    - Chicago macro-bits in the amber of memory, 1999 (Box 135)
    - Commodity-plus-quantity theories of money, undated (Box 135)
    - Commodity theory of money, undated (Box 135)
    - Cycles: In what degree myth?, 1980 (Box 135)
    - Differentiating two macro-theories of distribution, undated (Box 135)
    - Exposition of Keynes's General Theory, undated (Box 135)
    - Getting to an economy of post-war full employment, 1940s (Box 135)
    - The God that failed? Macroeconomic distribution models, 1976 (Box 135)
    - The god that failed: macroeconomic theories of income distribution, undated (Box 135)
    - Inflationary gap, undated (Box 135)
    - Instability of the lagged inventory model, 1959 (Box 135)
    - An integrated macro-micro model, 1963 (Box 135)
    - Macroeconomic theories of income distribution, undated (Box 135)
    - Modern theory of income, 1942 (Box 135)
    - Nature of business cycles, 1982 (Box 135)
    - Non-existent macro production functions when reality is far from ultra-surrogate paradigms, 1986 (Box 135)
    - Notes on national income, 1950 (Box 135)
    - Price and quality index, 1960s (Box 135)
    - Prices of factors and goods in general equilibrium, undated (Box 135)
    - A program for post-war full employment, 1944-1945 (Box 135)
    - Re Pigou's 1941 review of Keynes's General Theory, 1942-1943 (Box 135)
    - Research in macroeconomics, 1968 (Box 135)
    - Roemer's critique, 1986 (Box 136)
    - A tendency to over borrow, 1970 (Box 136)
    - A thank you note (re: GNP), 1971 (Box 136)
    - A unique business cycle of determinate amplitude and period: the 1940 Kaldor Limit Cycle generalized to possess trend, 1985 (Box 136)
  - Marx
    - Analytical Marxism: the Morishima version, 1970s (Box 136)
    - Challenge problem concerning non-existence of a consistent tableau of reproduction à la 1876 Marx, 1986 (Box 136)
    - A concise history of the Transformation Problem, 1989 Feb. (Box 136)
    - Foreword to a biography of Karl Marx, 1992 (Box 136)
    - Logic of the historical Transformation Problem: Exchange ratios under single commodity production, 1982 (Box 136)
    - Karl Marx, 1990s (Box 136)
    - Marx, undated (Box 136)
    - Marx, 1982 (Box 136)
    - Marx and competitive price, 1981 (Box 136)
    - Marx on Smith, 1982 (Box 136)
    - The Marxian Transformation Problem, with joint products, variable techniques, and altering demand, 1975 (Box 136)